this guy has produced videos exposing
trading gurus and the trading channel
has ended up in a couple of those videos
now let me start off by saying I have no
problem with this guy or with anything
that he is trying to do with his channel
I just think he's pointing at the wrong
person when pointing at me and that
seems obvious for me to think I get that
but in this video what I plan to do is
share some facts share some differences
and opinions that him and I have and
essentially share my side of this story
I have only scared through his videos
but I know at some point he's at least
insinuated that I was not a profitable
Trader so let's go ahead and squash that
first so here we are on my myfxbook as
you can see this is a real account with
aanda I'll reload the page a couple of
times just for good measure and as you
can see we have a
91.4 nearly a
91.4% return in a little over a year on
this account now just because I want to
turn this into a lesson I think it's a
little silly for me to do an entire
video with zero lesson just defending
myself if that's what you want to call
it so what I'm going to do is scroll
down to our monthly here and we're going
to go to 2023 so that I can give a
lesson in with this video look at the
trading here in 2023 as you'll see
trading is a bit of a roller coaster and
the problem is that most of us even
including me as a beginner in the
trading world come from a 9 to-5 job
where you're getting a consistent
paycheck once every couple of weeks
maybe once once a week but you were
getting a consistent check from an
employer whereas with trading as you can
see January I only made 1% I had a
couple of losing months in September and
October the inconsistency involved in
trading makes it even more difficult for
you to master trading psychology and
master your mindset when going through
periods months two months in a row for
me September and October in 2023 were
negative that is difficult to get
through and come out the other side with
a solid trading mindset and with solid
discipline something else I want to show
you if I click on I think it was
September look at the amount of Trades I
took in September down here at the
bottom we have three 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11
12 13 14 15 16 17 I can't remember where
I started somewhere around 20 trades
between 18 and 20 trades happened in
September of last year and I lost
4.5% in that month what I want you to
see from that think about how much work
that was to go through the month and
place nearly 20 trades it was a lot of
work it was a lot of analysis it was a
lot of trading for me I swing trade
between two to five trades a week is
normally what I do now check out
November in November I had far less
trades 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 but on
12 trades in November I made
29.4% that's the roller coaster that
trading is and the reason I want to
point that out is because with almost
any other career in the world the more
work you put in the more money you'll
make that's not always the case with
trading with trading it depends on
multiple factors including how the
market is reacting to the specific
strategies you're using let me give you
an example if you trade a trend
continuation strategy and the market
begins to consolidate you're going to
have losing months even if you have 20
plus trades and you're a swing Trader
but if the market is trending and you
trade Trend continuation you can make
30% on 12 trades in that single month
and so just keep in mind throughout your
entire trading career that trading isn't
a nine-to-five job and there is no
guarantee that you're going to make a
specific amount every single month the
better way to look at it is take your
combined gain throughout the year and
then divide it by 12 to get what would
be an average month for you in terms of
trading but as you can see I am a
profitable Trader the next thing he
talks about is a little bit funny in my
opinion and that is targeting beginners
now first off the reason 90 to 95% of my
content is catered to beginner or
struggling Traders is because those are
the Traders I want to help but second
off who else do you think is on YouTube
consuming trading related content like
do you think professional Traders are
out here scouring YouTube for more
information about trading probably not
right so that's just the only audience
that exists for trading related content
it is beginners and struggling Traders
those are the only people that watch
anything on YouTube about trading so
it's not that I am targeting beginners
beginner and struggling Traders are the
only people here and beginner and
struggling Traders are the people that I
want to help with my content so although
I can't speak for any of the other
channels that he talks about in these
videos exposing forx gurus at least for
me and my motivation for conducting
content meant for beginner and
struggling Traders the reason is just
that I want to help beginner and
struggling Traders and they are the only
people here in an earlier video he
pointed out that I made money on YouTube
and he insinuated that I tried to hide
that from any of my followers because I
was not a profitable Trader not the case
at all I am a profitable Trader and I've
never tried to hide the fact that I make
money on YouTube now I can't speak for
anyone else that he's ever made videos
on maybe there are Traders out there
that don't want you to know they make
money on YouTube but I don't mind that
you know I do make money on YouTube at
this point in 2023 I would assume that
everyone knows how YouTube works if you
don't essentially if you have a decent
following get a large amount of views
and you have your channel monetized you
are making money and even though it's
not something I've shared I've just
always assumed that people knew I was
making money from YouTube and the crazy
thing is the amount a channel makes is
essentially public information you can
go to this free site socialblade.com so
let's type in my channel the trading
channnel and let's see what the
estimated revenue is of my channel it
says between $350 and $5.6 th000 by the
way that's off we doubled that in last
month but it's not something I've ever
tried to hide it's just not something
I've ever thought I needed to mention
and the last thing I'm going to hit on
is marketing now I never thought i' was
going to do a marketing video on this
channel at all the only thing I ever
released in terms of videos on this
channel is content that I hope can help
you become a better Trader that's what
I've always done but yes I have an
online course that I sell which means I
have an online business and in that
business I use marketing marketing is
how any businesses run now let me
explain a bit about marketing this is
some of the things he talked about which
is in marketing just just discount
trading completely essentially what
every company in the world does when it
comes to their business just business
101 is they have leads these leads
normally come from one of two places one
would be organic leads like free content
they provide for YouTube Instagram Tik
Tok that would be an organic lead is
someone watching that content or paid
leads paid leads come from people that
run ads you've seen ads on YouTube
before those would be paid leads so the
way that a business normally makes
profit is those leads eventually become
customers and the way that works is most
of the time for online businesses at
least the company will provide some type
of free content that hopefully provides
value to that lead and when that person
has consumed enough free content if they
have found it to be extremely valuable
then there is a small chance that they
will decide to purchase something from
that company in our case it is a course
so there's a small chance that you
decide that you want to buy our course
essentially every business in the world
uses marketing if youve ever bought
anything from Best Buy they probably
sent you an email since when they're
having a promotion on something so he
talked about something else called lead
magnets a lead magnet would be something
like the beginner course that I have
that we offer I see that as something
very valuable to beginners or struggling
Traders so what happens is you click
that link you go to a page you put in
your email we email you that course for
free and now you are what is called a
warm lead these warm leads are a person
that a company will normally send
promotional offers to now on our email
list we also send you a bunch of free
stuff and other free information and
every now and then we'll send you some
type of promotional offer if we're
running like a Black Friday sale or
something of that nature and that is
marketing 101 and yes I have an online
business and yes I use Marketing in that
business now I want to talk about what
he calls fabricated demand The Limited
space available in the university is
real and the reason for that is because
I only have so much time and I answer
every single trading related question
from any of the clients in the
University anytime they have questions
that are related to trading so that is
the reason for the limited space
available but one thing that he did talk
about that hit a a little hard is there
used to be a timer under this video and
I'll put a screenshot up so you can see
it and above the timer it said space
only guaranteed for blank amount of time
I think it was like 55 minutes now
whenever I first put the timer on the
page I did not see it as a way to
fabricate demand I saw it as a different
way to express that there was limited
space available but I can see how that
would be misleading so because of that
what I want to do is if you purchase the
university because of the timer on on
the page and you're currently not
satisfied with your purchase just go
ahead and send us an email to the
support email you received with your
welcome email and we will get your money
refunded ASAP it was never my intention
to be misleading so again if you are not
satisfied with your purchase and you
decided to purchase because the timer
was on the page then just send us an
email to the support email that came
with your welcome email and the support
email you can find in the introduction
video of the course and we will get you
100% refund ASAP now there were were a
couple of other things he talked about
in these videos that just don't even
apply to me uh for instance something
called wealth flaunting which is
something I've literally never done on
this channel at all or on Instagram or
anywhere else and another thing
was oh only showing winning trades if
you've been a part of the channel for a
while you know that I show losing trades
all the time and I also just talked
about losing trades at the very
beginning of this video when going over
my months in 2023 where I lost money
during those months I lost money meaning
yes I lose trades so I never pretend
that I only win trades with any of the
strategies I trade or with my trading in
general but just to reiterate I have
absolutely no problem with this guy or
what he is doing I just wanted to share
what I consider my side of the story and
finally to recap I am in fact a
profitable Trader I do want to help
beginner and struggling Traders so a
majority of my content is catered to
beginner and struggling Traders I do
make money from YouTube and I do use
Marketing in my own online business and
to be completely clear I make money from
the online business I make money from
YouTube and I make money from Trading
now if for any reason at all you have a
problem with that as I said at the very
beginning of this video Everyone's
entitled their opinion and if you have
an issue with anything I've said in this
video then that is completely
understandable and I wish you the best
of luck in your future as a Trader and
if you're on the flip side of that coin
then I promise the next video will be
all about trading I wish you the best of
luck in your future trades I hope you
trade green happy New Year and I'll talk
to you in the next video